your dental coverage
first let's take a closer look at the
manulife dental insurance that you'll be
entitled to under the combo plus starter
plan the coverage will go into effect at
the age of 17 for those living in prince
edward island while those who live in
newfoundland are able to get coverage
starting at the age of 13.
if you and your family live in nova
scotia dental coverage can begin as
early as age 11. you'll be covered for
up to 70 of your total cost of some
dental services with a maximum service
cost of 575
services include dental cleanings
scalings fillings exams and polishing
you'll also get recall visits once every
nine months
so this plan is best for those who don't
need extensive dental work or who don't
expect to pay much for their overall
dental services
the good news you'll receive accidental
dental coverage for up to two thousand
dollars per year
your vision benefits with manulife
personal health insurance
now let's examine the personal health
insurance benefits that you'll get with
the commvo plus starter plan when it
comes to vision coverage
you'll be covered for up to seventy
dollars worth of fees associated with
visiting your optometrist for two
consecutive years
if you wear glasses they will be able to
be repaired under the coverage if
they've gotten broken or scratched
this is only applicable however if you
purchase both frames and lenses that are
a part of the flex care vision benefit
you'll also be able to get a 150 dollar
maximum for two years towards getting
those prescription lenses frames for
your glasses having laser eye surgery or
getting your contact lenses
manulife flex care combo plus starter
and prescription drugs
if you've been prescribed prescription
medication to help you to manage a more
chronic condition
then we know that the coverage you'll
receive is one of the most important
things you look at when choosing an
insurance plan
you'll be able to be covered for generic
prescriptions
while certain brand name drugs are
covered you will need to pay the generic
equivalent price in order to get them
your coverage under the starter plan is
up to 70 on the first 750 you'll spend
on your prescriptions you'll be able to
get coverage up to a maximum of 525
dollars per individual within a year
be aware however that certain types of
prescription drugs are excluded from
this plan
you will not be able to get coverage for
drugs relating to quitting smoking nor
will you be able to get coverage for
over-the-counter medication or anything
that doesn't require a kind of
prescription from a medical professional
you will also not be covered for birth
control pills or pills relating to any
kind of fertility issue
additional benefits
while dental vision and prescription
drug coverage are some of the most
important aspects of this plan
you'll be entitled to other forms of
coverage too
this includes unlimited ground
transportation in an ambulance when
you're heading to the hospital and a
four thousand dollars maximum if you
need to be airlifted to the hospital
should you find that you or a loved one
is in need of in-home care you'll be
able to be covered based on a yearly
increasing basis
in the first year of your coverage
you'll get a maximum of one thousand
dollars in year two you'll be covered
for one thousand three hundred dollars
by the time you reach the fifth year and
beyond of your coverage
your home care costs will be covered up
to three thousand dollars
additionally you'll be able to get a
maximum of six months of lifeline
personal response services every three
years
this is especially helpful if you're a
senior or need to cover the health care
expenses of a senior under your plan
you'll also be covered for a 400
maximum of hearing aids for four
consecutive years under the plan
should an accidental death or
dismemberment occur
if the person is under the age of 65 you
could get up to 25 000
if they're a child or over the age of 65
you'll get ten thousand dollars
want to learn more about your manulife
health and dental insurance options
we hope that this video has helped you
to better understand the personal health
insurance coverage that you're entitled
to under the manulife flex care combo
plus starter plan
as you can see this is one of the more
affordable options
though it doesn't provide as much
coverage as some of the other plans
offered by manulife it's perfect for
those who don't get need extensive
coverage
it's also ideal for those who are buying
their own insurance for the first time
want to learn more about the many types
of health and dental insurance canada
has to offer
we've got you covered
be sure to spend some time on our
website to explore other plans and find
the option that will keep you covered in
any situation
[Music]
you